<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac on ./sigterm.sh</title>
    <link>/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac on ./sigterm.sh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Git man pages on OS X</title>
      <link>/2010/04/15/getting-git-manpages-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/04/15/getting-git-manpages-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some reason the OS X install of Git doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the manpages. Here is how I installed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a ZFS filesystem with Time Machine</title>
      <link>/2009/10/04/using-a-zfs-filesystem-with-time-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/10/04/using-a-zfs-filesystem-with-time-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This simple how-to explains how to get your Time Machine backups working with a ZFS filesystem. This allows you to use the features of ZFS filesystems for your Time Machine backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note this is for Mac OS X - Snow Leopard.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New addition to the family</title>
      <link>/2009/09/05/new-addition-to-the-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/09/05/new-addition-to-the-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after much anticipation, many tireless weeks of spec checking and a whole bunch of money I was really glad to be on the receiving end of a brand spanking new 17&amp;rdquo; MacBook Pro!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it has been less than 72 hours this is (so far) truly the most amazing piece of computer equipment I have ever owned, honestly worth every single cent! The initial setup was completely flawless and only took a few minutes. The graphics, resolution and performance are exceptional, in fact I haven&amp;rsquo;t even had to switch over from the standard &amp;ldquo;on-board&amp;rdquo; video card to the higher end controller yet, despite putting the GPU through a thorough beating, testing out the Quake 4 demo :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>